<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Ben Krajacich</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Ben Krajacich</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Ben Krajacich</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/project/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Using historic data to map malaria seasonality</title>
      <link>/project/seasonal.malaria/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/seasonal.malaria/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent publication from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/nature24059&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Snow &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; put forth a huge data set on the prevalence of &lt;em&gt;Plasmodium falciparum&lt;/em&gt; malaria in sub-Saharan Africa since 1900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big portion of the work I currently focus on is related to the seasonal transmission dynamics of malaria, hinging on the dry-season behavior of &lt;em&gt;Anopheles coluzzii&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Anopheles gambiae&lt;/em&gt; s.s. mosquitoes in Mali. I wanted to see if from this data set I could get a better handle on defining the transmission season in Mali and across Africa ( &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/nature15535&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;especially as much of the malaria transmission is seasonal across Africa&lt;/a&gt; ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch this space as I flesh out some of the ideas, but as a brief snippet here is a k-nearest neighbor smoothed figure of monthly malaria transmission using data from 1990 on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/posts/16-OCt-17.allknn.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal change in the microbiome of *Anopheles coluzzii*</title>
      <link>/project/microbiome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/microbiome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a project I took over once I got to the NIH looking at how the mosquito microbiome changes seasonally in areas of Mali either with permanent, year-round water, or in areas with no known water for ~7 months of the year. This work was done in hopes to better understand the dry season persistence mechanisms of &lt;i&gt;Anopheles&lt;/i&gt; spp. mosquitoes, with hopes to move into understanding the impacts of this state on malaria transmission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look for future work with whole genome sequencing data!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
